# Kristopher L. Lucas MT(ASCP)

Brookhaven, Ga Phone: (404) 550-5082 E-mail: klucas72@hotmail.com

# **QUALIFICATIONS**

Bachelors of Science degrees in Medical Technology and Network Communications and Management with twenty years of laboratory and IT experience in diverse facilities. Expertise in technical and management in a diverse environment. Areas of expertise include:

Windows Server Administrator Cisco Routers and switches

Full Stack Web Development Linux Redhat Server Administrato

Languages include: CSS, HTML Javascript, Express JS, JSON

### **CERTIFICATION**

National Registry

Project Management Certificate

Project Medium Society for Clinical Pathology #03628940

University of Georgia

July, 2017

Georgia Institute of Technology

July 2021

### **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

**Network Administrator** Maintained, monitored and performed administrative tasks for small

business Servers for clients in various environments. Knowledge of various transmission and routing protocols such as OSPF and RIP.

**Software Implementation** Deployed and set up software database packages on customer

**Specialist/Consultant** network. Performed customer oriented training after deployment and

provided post installation support for any user questions or concerns

**Full Stack Web Developer** Created and developed web applications for public and private use.

Porfilio & Projects: <a href="https://klucas72.github.io/Portfolio/">https://klucas72.github.io/Portfolio/</a>

Project 1: <a href="https://klucas72.github.io/5-Day-forecast-application/">https://klucas72.github.io/5-Day-forecast-application/</a>

- •5 day forecast app using JavaScript, html, and CSS. Enter city name and you will receive current and 5 day forecast for that city
- •HTML was injected into framework with JavaScript

Project 2: <a href="https://sranson.github.io/recipe-finder/">https://sranson.github.io/recipe-finder/</a>

- •Recipe finder for all types of cuisine. Choose from the dropdown menus to pick your food and cocktail items.
- •Worked with a team to create application.
- •Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, with Bootstrap framework

GitHub Profile: <a href="https://github.com/klucas72">https://github.com/klucas72</a>

### **HISTORY**

# Software Systems Technical Immucor, Inc.

2013 to present

# **Specialist**

Accomplishments:

- Analyzed and troubleshot MiaFora Servers for configuration network communications issues. Worked with international customers resolving their issues.
- Installed software using SQL for database, IIS, Redhat OS configurations
- Trained customers on the use and maintenance of LIS interface software.
- Project manager for setting up and installing software database package on customer networks.
- Setup and configured instrument interfaces (LIS) for lab instruments to talk to customer laboratory information systems.

### **Network Administrator**

Alpha Group/Altair Advanced Ind. 2012 to 2013 *Accomplishments:* 

- administered domain policies, set permissions, roles, and access to various network resources. Installed complete wireless network for customers.
- Maintained and troubleshot network traffic issues for the domain as well as set up and maintained network servers.

# **Network Admin/Engineer**

Toph Tech Consulting *Accomplishments:* 

2011 to present

- administered domain policies, set permissions, roles, and access to various network resources. Installed complete wireless network for organization.
- Maintained and troubleshot network traffic issues for the domain as well as set up and maintained network servers.

### **EDUCATION**

Network Communications and Management Medical Technology Project Management Certificate Full Stack Web Development Certificate DeVry University, Atlanta, Ga 2007-2012 Indiana State University, Terre Haute, IN 1991–1995 University of Georgia July, 2017 Georgia Institute of Technology July 2021